Guide to the Esther M. Lederberg papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Esther M. Lederberg papers
1906-2013
1937-1998
SC0874
Lederberg, Esther M.
31 Linear feet
Collection includes class notes and lab notebooks from her education at Hunter College, 1939-42, Stanford University, 1944-46, and the University of Wisconsin, 1948-50; notes and lab notebooks from subsequent research, primarily with plasmids, 1950 on; records from the Plasmid Reference Center; correspondence; articles and reprints; photographs both professional and personal; family documents; and other materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Esther Miriam Zimmer Lederberg, PhD, professor emeritus of microbiology and immunology at the Stanford University School of Medicine, earned her AB at Hunter College in 1942. She then came to Stanford to study genetics, earning her MA in 1946. She earned her PhD at the University of Wisconsin, Madison in 1950. Among her achievements was the discovery of lambda phage, a virus that infects E. coli bacteria. Esther and Joshua Lederberg both joined the Stanford medical school faculty in 1959; they were divorced in 1966. In addition to her teaching duties, she directed the Plasmid Reference Center at Stanford medical school from 1976 to 1986. She was also the American Cancer Society Senior Dernham Fellow from 1968 to 1970. She died in 2006.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes class notes and lab notebooks from her education at Hunter College, 1939-42, Stanford University, 1944-46, and the University of Wisconsin, 1948-50; notes and lab notebooks from subsequent research, primarily with plasmids, 1950 on; records from the Plasmid Reference Center; correspondence; articles and reprints; photographs both professional and personal; family documents; and other materials.
Access Terms
Lederberg, Esther M.; Stanford University. School of Medicine--Faculty.; Laboratory notes.; Microbiology.; Notebooks.; Plasmids --Genetics.
Collection Contents
- Original accession, Accession ARCH-2007-158
  - Botanical notes and drawings, Hunter College, 1939 Dec (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Botanical drawings, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Invertebrate zoology I and II, Drs. Elliott and McKinnsey, drawings, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invertebrate zoology I and II, Drs. Elliott and McKinnsey, notes part 1, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invertebrate zoology I and II, Drs. Elliott and McKinnsey, notes part 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mycology notebook, Hunter College, Spring 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Botanical drawings, observed at New York Botanical Gardens, Feb. 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Botanical drawings, New York Botanical Gardens Museum, March 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Neurospora [genetics] notebook, Stanford, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biology 107, Dr. G. W. Beadle, Stanford, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Biology 250, Dr. G. W. Beadle, Stanford, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Anatomy 141, Dr. C. Danforth, Stanford, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Physiology reading, [1945] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Microbiology I, Stanford, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Microbiology II, Stanford, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Comparative and experimental marine biology, Dr. R. Watterson, Hopkins Marine Station, summer 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Physiology of bacteria, F. W. Wilson, U. of Wisconsin, 1948 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Physiology of bacteria, F. W. Wilson, U. of Wisconsin, 1948 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Genetic Control of Mutability notes, 2/1948-6/1949: pp. 1-60 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Genetic Control of Mutability notes, 2/1948-6/1949: pp. 61-150 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Genetic Control of Mutability notes, 2/1948-6/1949: pp. 151-224 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Genetic Control of Mutability notes, 2/1948-6/1949: pp. 225-300 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Genetic Control of Mutability notes, 2/1948-6/1949: pp. 301-399 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Genetic Control of Mutability notes, 2/1948-6/1949: pp. 400-499 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Four botanical specimens collected in New York and New Jersey, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Books
    - E. Z. Lederberg, Genetic Control of Mutability in the Bacterium Escherichia Coli. Ph.D. dissertatation, University of Wisconsin, 1950. (Box 5)
    - Plasmids; Medical and Theoretical Aspects; Third International Symposium on Antibiotic Resistance, 1976 [Lederberg article p. 389] (Box 5)
    - Horace Freeland Judson, The Eighth Day of Creation [Lederberg annotations p. 377 and 386] (Box 5)
    - 8th International Conference on Bacilli. Program. Sponsored by Genencor International, Inc. July 8-12, 1995 Stanford, California. (Box 5)
  - Notebooks
    - Bryophytes and Pteridophytes, lab notebook, Hunter College, Jan. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Evolution notebook, Stanford, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - University of Wisconsin-Madison lab notebook 1, Sept. 1950-Jan. 1952 (1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - UWM lab notebook 1, Sept. 1950-Jan. 1952 (2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - UWM lab notebook 1, Sept. 1950-Jan. 1952 (3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - UWM lab notebook 2, Oct. 1956-July 1957 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - UWM lab notebook 2, Oct. 1956-July 1957 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lab notebook (S1) 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lab notebook (S4) Jan.4 - April 4, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Lab notebook (S5) 1962-63, 1965, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lab notebook (S5) – folder 1 labeled "NSF Proposal" (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lab notebook (S5) – folder 2 labeled "MS" (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lab notebook (S6) 1966-71 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Lab notebook (S7) 1973 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Lab notebook (S7) 1973 (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Notebook (S8) "Molecular Properties of an F-Lac+-Tetracycline-Resistant Plasmid in E. coli and Salmonella typhimurium" drafts and background material. [Submitted on 4/20/73 to XIII International Congress of Genetics; presented in Berkeley Aug. 20-29, 1973] (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Lab notebook (S9), Jan. 30-May 31, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Lab notebook (S10), March 25-July 24, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lab notebook (S11) 1973-74 (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Lab notebook (S11) 1973-74 (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Lab notebook (S12) June 23-Oct. 4, 1974 (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lab notebook (S12) June 23-Oct. 4, 1974 (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Lab notebook (S13) Oct. 11-Dec. 4, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Lab notebook (S14) 1973-75 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Lab notebook (S15) Plasmid stock descriptions, 1973, 1974, 1975 and Index of Experiments 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Lab notebook (S16A) 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Lab notebook (S16B) 1975 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Lab notebook (S16B) 1975 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Lab notebook (S17) Nov. 4, 1975-April 28, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Lab notebook (S18) 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Lab notebook [Plasmid Reference Center] (PRC1) Dec. 13, 1976-Dec. 12, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 2) March 22-Sept. 15, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Lab notebook (PRC4) Nov. 3, 1976-Feb. 3, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lab notebook (PRC5) – Salmonella stock lists, SW Stab Collection list as of 7/76, E. coli linkage map dated 5/70, letter from EML to Bruce Holloway, 7/11/78 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Lab notebook [Plasmid Resource Center] (PRC6) – Kevin Reynolds worksheets, Sept. 16, 1971-July 28, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lab notebook (PRC8) 1978-79 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Plasmid Resource Center correspondence (notebook PRC7) [this folder includes paperwork in support of a grant request to the NIH 4/29/76] Feb. 24, 1975-Jan. 23, 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Plasmid Resource Center correspondence (notebook PRC7) Feb. 24, 1975-Jan. 23, 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lab notebook: Tf54 – Tf77 (PRC9) 1979 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 10) Feb. 2-June 30, 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 10) Feb. 2-June 30, 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 11) May 11-Nov. 24, 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 11) May 11-Nov. 24, 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 12) Oct. 1976-Dec. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 13) Jan. 4, 1979-May 8, 1980 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 13) Jan. 4, 1979-May 8, 1980 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 14) May 2-Dec. 5, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 15) Feb. 1979-Jan. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Notebook – PRC office equipment and procedures (PRC 16A) early 1980s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Notebook – PRC office equipment and procedures (PRC 16B) early 1980s (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Notebook – stock records for EL, pseudo ED, plasmids (PRC 17) 1980-82 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Notebook – PRC lists and correspondence (PRC 18) April 1, 1980-Feb. 15, 1983 (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Notebook – PRC lists and correspondence (PRC 18) April 1, 1980-Feb. 15, 1983 (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Notebook – information and correspondence re Q (PRC 19) 1978-83 (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – information and correspondence re Q (PRC 19) 1978-83 (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 20) 1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Notebook – information and correspondence re Colicin Strains (PRC 21) 1976-84 (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Notebook – information and correspondence re Colicin Strains (PRC 21) 1976-84 (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Notebook – requests for PRC catalogs (PRC 22) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Notebook – correspondence 1981-89 including correspondence between EML and David Bradley 1989 (PRC 23) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Notebook – PRC database use information (PRC 24) 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – PRC miscellaneous correspondence (PRC 25) May 20, 1987-Jan. 12, 1994 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Notebook – PRC miscellaneous correspondence (PRC 25) May 20, 1987-Jan. 12, 1994 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 26) Feb. 26, 1992-July 1, 1998 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Lab notebook (PRC 26) Feb. 26, 1992-July 1, 1998 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Notebook – requests for prefixes (PRC 27) 1995-99 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Notebook – notes and miscellany (PRC 28) 1979-82 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Notebook SW1: Series GA, B C stock lists, experiments, "to do" list, tests, new stocks, and misc. reports, 1966 (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Notebook SW1, 1966 (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Notebook SW2: experiment logs, 1962-65, DNA tests, 1962-65, Boston Test 4/28/65, and multiple marker stock list, 9/19/63 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Notebook SW3: experiment logs, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Notebook SW4: lab notebook, Jan. 6-Sept. 3, 1964 (1 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Notebook SW4: lab notebook, Jan. 6-Sept. 3, 1964 (2 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Notebook SW4: lab notebook, Jan. 6-Sept. 3, 1964 (3 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Notebook SW5: lab notebook, Oct. 26, 1964-March 28, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Notebook SW6: lab notebook, Sept. 24-Dec. 21, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Notebook SW7: lab notebook, Nov. 28, 1961-Nov. 11, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Notebook SW8: lab notebook (stock sheets from 1956 recorded 3/56; experiment logs, Aug. 45-July 1961; and Natural F+ lines of E. coli 6/26/70) (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Notebook SW8: lab notebook (stock sheets from 1956 recorded 3/56; experiment logs, Aug. 45-July 1961; and Natural F+ lines of E. coli 6/26/70) (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Comparative vertebrate anatomy, lab notebook, Hunter College, Jan. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Embryology lab notebook, Hunter College, June 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Genetics workbook, Biol. 107 / Anat. 141 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Physiology (Biol. 106), notebook and exam, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Robert A. Altenbern, 1969 that accompanied the book "Entry and Control of Foreign Nucleic Acid" [symposium papers] 1969 (Box 5)
  - EML Laboratory plasmid stock records (S2) 1964-66 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Department of Medical Microbiology and Immunology Schedule of Speakers, and supporting correspondence (S3) Sept. 1965-Jan. 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratories Scheme for "Inc" plasmids (PRC3), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Notes from Cold Spring Harbor Symposia (CSH1), 1949-55 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: M. L. Morse, 1956-58 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: M. L. Morse, 1959-61 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: M. L. Morse, 1963-70 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: M. L. Morse (includes one photo of EL), 1972-93 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: M. L. Morse and biographical info, 1955-63, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Images – photocopies (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Photographs – 1 print, 2 printed scans (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Articles on plasmids and 1 email exchange following EL’s death (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - EML – C.V. 1982; lecture announcement 1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - EML – reprints and abstracts (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, mostly re Tn allocations, 1982-88 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, EML with Alex and Pam Reisner 1986 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Karen Fahrner re Escherichia coli K-12, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - ASM News, miscellaneous articles from (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Appendices for a possible grant (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Bachman, Barbara – pedigree for Wisconsin strains, correspondence and lists, 1971-72 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Bacterial genetics, notes, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Delappe, Irving P. "Evolution of Support for Plasmid Research by the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases," 1981 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Department of Microbiology & Immunology – history ca. 1998 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Felix d’Herelle – article on him and list of phages (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Genetics – assorted articles, mostly from their series "Perspectives: Anecdotal, Historical and Critical commentaries on Genetics" (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Lederberg, et. al., "Molecular Properties of an F’Lac-Tetracycline resistance Plasmid in E. coli and Salmonella Typhimurium" – text for slides (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Plasmid Reference Center – "News and Announcements" 1978 and letter by EML to Dr. Monica Riley, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Plasmids – reprint, notes, drafts and other items, 1968-86 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Pseudomonas plasmids – notes for talk, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - WFCC World Data Center – list, brochure, card (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Hunter College, Class of 1942 – commencement program and "Hunter Memories" ca. 1992 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - High School yearbook, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Plasmid Reference Center – notes on colicins, 1987-81 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - PRC data sheets for #302-309 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - PRC data sheets for #310-398 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - PRC data sheets for #331-350 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - PRC data sheets for #335-370 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - PRC data sheets for #371-395 ((incomplete, not in order) 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - PRC data sheets for #371-395 ((incomplete, not in order) 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - PRC data sheets for #400-475 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - PRC data sheets for #425-447 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - PRC data sheets for #476-600 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Articles from research using PRC stains, stocks, or plasmids, 1982-84 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Articles from experiments involving insertion elements, transposons, 1985-91 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Articles from research using transposons, insertion sequences, 1983-84 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Articles from research using insertion elements, transposons, insertion sequences, 1981-96 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Articles from research using insertion elements, plasmids, transposons, insertion sequences, genetic mapping, in E. coli, salmonella, pseudomonas, 1977-82 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Articles from research using genetic mapping, insertion sequences, transposons, bacteriophages, and plasmids; salmonella typhimurim, 1908-83 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Labigne-Roussel, Agnes, and Courvalin, Patrice, "Is15, a new insertion sequence widely spread in r plasmids of gram-negative bacteria," review proof, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Articles on E. coli, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - "History of Microbiology in the North-East Branch of The American Society for Microbiologists," Proceedings of the 70th Meeting of the ASM, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Articles, possibly re Tn/IS reports, 1985-98 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Articles from research using insertion elements, transposons, insertion sequences or recombination, 1979-94 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Assorted articles by others (1 of 3) (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Assorted articles by others (2 of 3) (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Assorted articles by others (3 of 3) (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Slides
    - Original slide box 1: People, 1957-79 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 2: Travel 1957-59 – Sweden, Europe, England, India, U.S.; and people mostly 1958 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 3: Travel 1962 – Spain, Venice (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 4: [Unlabeled] 1961-64 – possibly her Stanford home, and California travel (Point Reyes, Yosemite) (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 5: only one slide, probably from Australia (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 6: Travel 1957 – Paris and other places in France (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 7: Travel – American West 1950, Copenhagen 1959, London and England 1958-59; a few of people (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 8: Mexico 1960, Oaxaca 1962, and miscellaneous slides (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 9: Europe 1957-58 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 10: Stockholm, Italy, and other places 1958-59; two slides of construction of SUMC (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 11: Travel 1958-62 – Spain, Italy, Switzerland and other places (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 12: Stanford images 1958-62 – her home, Pine Hill, and people (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 13: Japan 1962 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 14: Japan 1962, India ca. 1959 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 15: People and assorted travel (U.S. and abroad) 1951-59 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 16: Australia and Fiji 1957 (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 17: People 1957-63 (at Stanford, on travels, at conferences, etc.) (Box 21)
    - Original slide box 18: Madison, WI people and scenes 1951-62 (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 19: Miscellaneous 1950-51 – Woods Hole, Stanford, SF Bay Area, California travel (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 20: People, undated; Australia and many unlabeled (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 21: Australia, Fiji, Hawaii (1957) and many unlabeled (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 22: Stanford (house at 716 Alvarado, including snow in January 1962), construction of house by ocean 1964, Mexico 1960, construction on Stanford campus 1958, 1 slide of C. C. Spicer 1/19/53 (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 23: People 1950-62, Mexico 1962, Hurricane 1954, U. S. travel 1950-59, other unidentified travel (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 24: Groups of people and individuals late 1950s, Australia, Bangkok, Calcutta and many unidentified (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 25: Assorted 1950-58 – Berkeley, Paris, California travel; J. F. Kennedy’s inauguration 1961; Scotland; construction of ocean side house 1964; Stanford 1958-59 (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 26: People 1950-59, Mt. Evans trip 1955, assorted travel, hurricane 1954 (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 27: Australia, London, Hawaii 1957, and unlabeled images (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 28: Japan 1962 (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 29: Travel 1958-59 – Stockholm, Great Britain, Scotland (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 30: Travel – Mexico 1960, Italy 1959, Lassen Park 1950 and others (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 31: Travel, assorted, mostly unlabeled (Box 22)
    - Original slide box 32: People 1963-61, construction of ocean side house 1964 (Box 22)
    - Photocopies of index notes from inside original slide boxes (Box 22)
  - Artifacts
    - Autograph album of Esther [Lederberg], 1934 (Box 23)
    - Autograph album of Pauline Geller, 1917 (Box 23)
    - Medals – Pasteur Award to Joshua and Ester Lederberg 1956; one to Esther Zimmer from Repbulique Francaise Ministere des Affaires Etrangeres [noted as for "expertise in French"] (Box 23)
    - Gavel – Dr. Esther M. Lederberg, President Stanford Chapter SIGMA XI (Box 23)
    - Box of name stamps for Esther M. Lederberg (Box 23)
    - Door name plates: (1) Esther M. Lederberg and (2) Plasmid Reference Center (Box 23)
    - 2 lab coats of EML [in preservation box from dry cleaner] (Box 24)
  - Books [not listed] (Box 25)
  - Books [not listed] (Box 26)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2008-047
  - Photograph albums (7), including proofs of images taken at 1958 Nobel Prize Award Ceremony (item 1-5), 1958-90 (Box 1)
  - Photograph albums (7), including some group shots of the Stanford Department of Medical Genetics (item 2-6), circa 1960-88 (Box 2)
  - Photograph albums (7), 1969-87 (Box 3)
  - Photograph albums (6), 1976-1982 (Box 4)
  - Photograph albums (4), 1969-1976 (Box 5)
  - Large format slides for presentation "Day of the PLASMIDS" (Box 5)
  - Box of index cards of names and addresses of Plasmid Resource Center customers and contacts (Box 5)
  - Reprints of journal articles (Box 5)
  - Family photos, 1937-1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1950 EMBO, 1977 Plasmids conference (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photos: friends and colleagues (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Misc. loose photos of colleagues (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photos: friends and colleagues, circa 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Loose photos of Colleagues, Esther, Alexander Hollaender; Gordon, and conferences (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Japanese announcement; article about John Platt (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Japanese photo of Esther (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum-vitae (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - General Microbiology class notes (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Class notes (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Unbound copies of Microbial Genetics Bulletin, folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Unbound copies of Microbial Genetics Bulletin, folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Unbound copies of Microbial Genetics Bulletin, folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Japanese Photos, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album, Colleagues, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vacation photos; colleagues; Stanford University construction (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1896-1982 Family David Zimmer Pauline Geller (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Trip to Porto Vallarta, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Trip to France (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Early photos, Wisconsin years (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Photo album, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Esther M. Zimmer Lederberg reprints of papers (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Photo album with label 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Envelope of misplaced slides (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Unbound copies of Microbial Genetics Bulletin, folder 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Unbound copies of Microbial Genetics Bulletin, folder 5 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Allocations of Tn and IS; Plasmid Reference Center Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Plasmid number Allocations (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Personal records of Esther Lederberg (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - PRC papers and correspondence (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - PRC forms and regulations (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - PRC documents (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Copies of three papers (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - PRC announcements (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Continuation of IS allocations (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - PRC cultures and acquisitions (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - PRC allocations (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Plasmid allocations, 1991-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)